Ashish Mishra

Nationality: Indian Date of birth: 28/02/2001 Gender: Male Phone number: (+91) 7277159358

Email address: ashish.bipulmishra@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish- mishra-487b1b19b/

Github: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish- mishra-487b1b19b/

• Work: Kamal Model Sr Sec School , Nawada , New Delhi, 110059 New Delhi (India)

ABOUT ME

Software developer professional with 3+ Experience in Python Machine Learning, LLM and GUI Development. Consistent in delivering clean, error-free code to meet current or expected needs. Well-versed in Software trends and confident in multiple language, frameworks, and programming tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

City: Los Angels | Country: United States

Python Data Scientist

[23/02/2024 - Current]

- Led the successful implementation of SFT and DPO tasks at CharacterAI, leading to a 40% increase in process efficiency.
- Utilized LLAMA 3.1 and RLHF methodologies at MetaAI to optimize operations and enhance productivity.
- Applied LLAMA and RLHF frameworks at Microsoft, resulting in a 20% improvement in task completion time.
- Actively collaborating with **Service Now** client to deliver impactful results through SFT, Complex Instructions Following, Complex Reasoning, AgenticAI, and Data Visualization tasks.

City: Faridabad | Country: India

Software developers

[16/08/2022 - 12/02/2024]

Python GUI Application with Tkinter PCAN Interface

- · Integrated the PCANBasic.dll library for communication between a controller and the GUI.
- Implemented test cases triggered by button clicks to send hex messages over the Controller Area Network (CAN).
- The entire project was based on Python, Tkinter.

Language Translator Using QML & PyQt

- Used Qt Linguist to generate QM files for language translations (e.g., French, Spanish, Japanese).
- Utilized Type Scripts file and Python in the project.
- Developed language translator application using QML and PyQt

Dashboard Application using C++ Qt and QML

- Created a user interface (UI) for a 7-inch cluster display application.
- Designed UI elements such as windows, menu buttons (up, down,
- home), gauges for fuel and temperature, a speedometer using
- canvas, and added time features and warning messages.
- Developed using C++ Qt and QML.

DMS (Driver Monitoring System)

- Developed a Driver Monitoring System using machine learning and NVIDIA TAO Toolkit.
- Created an action recognition system for driver distraction detection. Collected real-time datasets and trained 2D RGB models with CNN 16 using 120 epochs. Leveraged computer vision and advanced algorithms for accurate results. Expanded expertise in machine learning, computer vision, and NVIDIA TAO Toolkit

Prutor@IITK - Kanpur, India - Kanpur, India

City: Kanpur | Country: India

AIML Internship and Training

[09/2021 - 11/2021]

E-mail Spam Filtering

- Here I have worked on a live project which was based on ML
- · This project was done during 6 weeks of summer training at Robustresults Pvt. Ltd an IITK incabulated Company

Technology worked on

- Python (Tkinter, PyQt, Django)
- LLM (SFT,RLHF,DPO,GPT- 4, LLAMA 3.1, RAG)
- AIML (Action Recognition, Face Recognition, OpenCV, NumPy, Panda & TensorFlow)
- JavaScript / TypeScript
- C++ QT/QML (Beginner Level)
- C(Basic)
- HTML and XML

Operating System, Framework & Tool Used:

- · Windows, Ubuntu
- QT Creator, Visual Code and Visual Studio.
- GIT

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

B.Tech CSE

KIPM College of Engineering and Technology [2018 – 2022]

City: Gorakhpur | Country: India | Final grade: 7.4

Intermediate/+2, Science - 2017

Kamla Rai Science College [2015 – 2017]

City: Gopalganj | Country: India

Matriculation

DAV High School, Gopalganj [2014 – 2015]

City: Gopalganj | Country: India

CERTIFICATION

[09/2021 - 11/2021]

AI & Machine Learning Prutor@IITK

This is a 4-week Certification Course with Project Work and Internship inMachine Learning & Al, 2 weeks of online live projects

[08/2019 - 12/2019]

Python Programming by E & ICT Academy, IIT Kanpur

This is a **MOOC Course**, In this course i learned python from basics.

[07/2021 - 09/2021]

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

AWS Training and Certification

[05/2019 - 06/2019]

C++/ C Language, NEW ERA-SHAHI MARKET, Gorakhpur, UP

This is a Summer Training, Durations of 45 DAYS

[08/2021 - 10/2021]

Full Stack Web Development

I had completed this course online at Udemy

[05/2020 - 06/2020]

Python For Data Science Certificates from GREYATOM

this course conducted by **AICTE** and Certificate of Completion from **GREYATOM**, Certificate ID: GA-1K12Z0DY2 (www.greyatom.com)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Hindi
Other language(s): English